<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home Page on The Actor Network</title><link>https://danielries.github.io/CSS_ProjectB/</link><description>Recent content in Home Page on The Actor Network</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://danielries.github.io/CSS_ProjectB/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data description</title><link>https://danielries.github.io/CSS_ProjectB/data-description/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielries.github.io/CSS_ProjectB/data-description/</guid><description>First of all, lets get familiar with the data used through the project. Every information we have stems from the data source, The Movie Data Base (TMDB), which covers a broad range of the film industry and it has built a reputation for being a well-known within the field. The main data of this project consists of information on the 5,000 most popular actors and information about movies from recent years (2010 and forward) they have participated, which results in around 30,000 movies in total.</description></item><item><title>Network analysis</title><link>https://danielries.github.io/CSS_ProjectB/network-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielries.github.io/CSS_ProjectB/network-analysis/</guid><description>Now with a better understanding of the data, the network can be created. The network consists of 5100 actors with a total of 23736 links that connect them. This is a lot to process and just to get a better idea of what this means, a visualization can be helpful. In the following figure of the network the actors are colored according to their country of birth.
The most important insight that can be gained from the visualization is that some clear groups are naturally made in the graph.</description></item><item><title>Text analysis</title><link>https://danielries.github.io/CSS_ProjectB/text-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielries.github.io/CSS_ProjectB/text-analysis/</guid><description>Now that the actor collaboration network have been explored (Check the Network page), it is time to delve deeper and finally put light on the forming of actor communities inside our network. As it can be seen on the Network page, the actors are forming some kinda of groupings among each other, where certain types of actors seems to be co-acting more than with others. We will here call these actor groupings of the network for &amp;ldquo;communities&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>